Riley Webber

+1 (949) 973-4403 | riley.webber@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/riley-webber

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY
EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

Meticulous Computer Science student with versatile and broad knowledge of programming languages, platforms, network systems, and data structures. Extensive background of advanced calculus techniques and applications in classical physics as well as algorithm optimizations. Experiences in National Speech and Debate competitions ensure strong presentation and collaborative skills to be an excellent team-player and leader.

EDUCATION

California State University - Fullerton, CA

B.S. Computer Science, May 2021 GPA: 3.71

Saddleback College, CA

A.S. Computer Science, May 2019 GPA: 3.23

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: C++, Java, Python, C, SQL, JavaScript, MATLAB, R, HTML, CSS

Frameworks/Tools: Git, Qt, React, MySQL, IntelliJ, Eclipse, Visual Studio, Arduino,

Linux/Unix systems

PROJECTS

NBA Tour Program

Saddleback College, Fall 2018

- Developed a tour program through NBA stadiums using Dijkstra's algorithm and modifying database functions hosted on an SQLite server.
- Continuous integration maintained using Travis CI.
- Sprints using Scrum from Agile methodology and sudden premise changes would be invoked
- Qt Creator used to create GUI interface and run program.

Music Visualizer

California State University Fullerton, Fall 2019

- Music visualizer using LEDs and Python 2.7 script to receive audio input, split into several different bands, then output RGB coding according to one of three designed settings.
- Data transmitted through ESP8266 Wi-Fi board coded with Arduino IDE.

Bulk Club Inventory Manager

Saddleback College, Spring 2018

- Implemented inventory program for mock business that would use SQL plugins and designed functions to allow user to add, modify, delete, binary sort, and binary search items.
- Program developed on Qt Creator along with GUI interface.
- · Agile methodology used to work cohesively as group

EXPERIENCE

Montage International – Studio

July 2018 - Present

Fine Dining Server / Server Attendant

- Maintained proficient knowledge of menu and wine selections to provide clientele with excellent pairing recommendations that suit their individual tastes.
- Work collaboratively with the restaurant team to uphold Forbes 5-Star as one of only 8 distinguished establishments in California.

The Cheesecake Factory

November 2016 – August 2018

Server / Cashier / Baker

 Provide personalized and meaningful experiences to all guests in high-pace environment by employing effective communication skills, anticipating needs, and maintain thorough knowledge of all menu items.

Lake Mission Viejo Association

May 2016 - August 2018

Lifeguard / Boat Operator

• Leadership role responsible for Junior Lifeguard program and boat maintenance in addition to daily safety responsibilities and medical knowledge within the scope of an EMR.

YMCA April 2014 – May 2016

Swim Coach / Lifeguard / Swim Instructor

- Youth Swim & Dive Program supervisor responsible for practice regiment and swim meet scheduling.
- Expected to be a role model for staff in multiple roles throughout facility.